Crystal Yan 408.899.9671 | yan.crystal.c@gmail.com

Product management and design leader focused on transforming organizations to become more customer-centric. Experience using behavioral science and artificial intelligence to create meaningful user experiences for B2B and B2C products globally.

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager & Product Design Manager — FiscalNote, Washington, DC MAR 2016 - PRESENT

- · Landed first enterprise client with total contract value (TCV) that grew company revenue by 10% by setting vision and roadmap of product portfolio generating > \$8M annual recurring revenue (ARR), including launching new EU, South America, and Asia product lines for web and mobile.
- Doubled product team in headcount and reduced ramp-up time for new hires by 50% by developing interviewer guides and onboarding program; report directly to COO/VP of Product.
- Designed new features and product lines that grew average contract value (ACV) from 43.54% from 2015 Q4 to 2016 Q3 by leading the full-stack design discovery process (lead design sprints, conduct qualitative and quantitative user experience (UX) research with interviews and metrics analysis; lead ideation and wireframing; create interactive high-fidelity prototypes, and test with users to validate hypotheses), leading delivery sprints with engineering and QA, and planning go-to-market strategy with marketing, sales, and client success teams.

Freelance Designer & Product Strategy Consultant — Independent, Remote FEB 2017-PRESENT

- Curriculum Design Consultant for the DC Mayor's Office Summer Youth Employment Program.
- Cofounder for Vento, LLC, a product studio launching Kai, an augmented reality (AR) travel app.
- UX Design Lead for MyHealthEd, Inc, a nonprofit transforming sex education with storytelling. Contributed to raising \$50K in funding and launching beta product by leading the UX and interaction design for an app designed for 13-14 year old low-income teens in rural areas.
- Design Lead for Rise, a civil rights NGO advocating for a Sexual Assault Survivors' Bill of Rights.

Associate Product Manager & UX Researcher/Designer — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- · Launched company's first iOS app in four months with one engineer by producing hi-fidelity prototypes, running usability testing and beta testing, and iterating based on user feedback.
- · Aligned executive team (heads of product, sales, client success, and marketing) by developing user personas that quide product strategy, marketing campaign targeting, and sales strategy.
- · Improved site performance and remove user interface (UI) inconsistencies and lines of legacy code by developing the first style guide, UI asset and UX pattern library.

Business Development Associate — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- · Contributed to company raising \$18 million in funding by consistently exceeding sales quotas and closing \$386,842 in new revenue (34% of company revenue) from new clients (Uber, Lyft, FireEye, Akin Gump, Coinbase) with shortest sales cycles, and increasing inbound leads by 36% by developing content marketing and improving SEO as interim Head of Marketing.
- Grew ACV by 76.82% by leading and developing training for 35+ new hires on optimal ways to structure pricing and contract terms in order to maximize ACV and improve cash flow.

Corporate Development Strategy — Sinovation Ventures, Beijing, China OCT 2012 - DEC 2013

· Diversified firm revenue by conducting analysis with recommendation to spin part of Dr. Kaifu Lee (former Google China CEO)'s VC firm's in-house UX team into an external UX studio.

Product Manager - Mobile, Standard Chartered Bank, Shanghai, China AUG 2012 - SEP 2012

- Increased inbound leads and reduced product support costs by leading product development & user testing for a bilingual (English/Mandarin) iPad app for small business owners.
- Cut development costs by 27% by analyzing vendor supplier data to identify excess expenses.

SKILLS

Management: Interviewing, Hiring, Training, Leading **Design Sprints** User Research: Data Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, User Testing **Design:** Interaction, UI & Visual (Sketch, Adobe CS), Mobile, Prototyping (InVision)

SPEAKING

StarsConf 2017 Santiago, Chile RubyConf 2017 Medellin, Colombia Grace Hopper 2017 Orlando, FL Scenic City Summit Chattanooga, TN **UXDC 2017** Washington, DC ULLConf 2016 Killarney, Ireland AIGA DotGovDesign Washington, DC Microsoft Research Beijing, China

AWARDS

McKinsey NGWL '17

EDUCATION

Amherst College BA, Economics, 2014 Tsinghua University International Affairs Beijing, Fall 2012 International Honors **Program Urban Planning &** Anthropology Delhi, Dakar, Buenos Aires, Spring 2013



Product management and design leader focused on transforming organizations to become more customer-centric. Experience using behavioral science and artificial intelligence to create meaningful user experiences for B2B and B2C products globally.